### CALEB CRUM

Greer, SC 29651

Phone: (608) 797 - 4737 | Email: caleb@paperlessfundraisers.com, ccrum@instructors.2u.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/caleb-crum/ | Github: https://github.com/ccrum292 |

#### SUMMARY

Level-headed, easy going, and inquisitive, I'm a Full-Stack Web Developer, Instructor and business owner, who leans toward back-end work, is successful in collaborative team environments and enjoys producing creative long-term solutions. I have proven experience developing web applications using all technologies in SERN and MERN stacks.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js, SQL

**Applications:** Bootstrap, Bulma, Materialize, Tailwindcss, JQuery, React.js, Next.js, Express.js, Handlebars.js, MySQL, Sequelize, Prisma, Supabase, GraphQL, MongoDB, Mongoose, FaunaDB, SendGrid, Git, GitHub, Heroku, Vercel

#### **PROJECTS**

#### Paperless Fundraisers, LLC (alpha) | Deployed Application

- Part Owner and Managing Member.
- Fundraising Simplified: An online system for running product selling fundraisers.
- Responsibilities: Designed and Implemented entire application.
- Tools / languages used: Next.js, MUI, Supabase, & Vercel

#### My-Flash-Cards GitHub | Deployed Application

- Flash Card App with a drag and drop folder system, rich card content (images, etc), and dynamic study session.
- Responsibilities: Designed and Implemented entire application.
- Tools / languages used: React, Redux, MUI, Node.js, Express, GraphQL, MongoDB/Mongoose, Heroku, and Namecheap

#### **E**XPERIENCE

# Full-Stack Web Developer, Part Owner and Managing Member Paperless Fundraisers, Ilc

2022 – Present Rock Hill, SC

- Full-Stack Web Development
- Database Design
- UI / UX Design

## Full-Stack Web Development Boot Camp Instructor edX / Vanderbilt

2020 – Present Charlotte, NC

- Educate students in HTML, CSS, JS, Node.js, React, SQL, and other web technologies
- Monitor and assist students in small group environments
- Maintain Class Git Repository
- TA from 2020 2023
- Lead Instructor 2023 Present

(CONTINUES)

# **Emergency Medical Technician Mecklenburg Emergency Medical Services**

2014 – 2019 Charlotte, NC

- Responded to medical emergencies and delivered patient care, support, and evaluation on scene and during transport to the hospital.
- Assessed the patient, determined the proper emergency care, and administered treatment.
- Transported patients safely between hospitals and care facilities.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Bootcamp Certificate:** UNCC Full-Stack Web Development, Charlotte, NC A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.